

SKILLS

- Team Work
- Problem-solving thinking
- Programing
- Machine Learning

LANGUAGES

- Portugese Native
- English Fluent
- Spanish Advanced

PACKAGES

- Author of the R package fableCount, for modeling counting time series. Available in: https://cran.rproject.org/web/packages/fableCount/ index.html
- Co-author of the R package MMCSD, for modeling complex longitudinal sample data. Available in: https://cran.rproject.org/web/packages/Mmcsd/ind ex.html

GUSTAVO ALMEIDA SILVA

STATISTICIAN





(13) 99683 - 4390 gustavoalmeidasilva@ice.ufjf.br giuthub.com/gustavo039



PROFILE

Student in the final semester of the Statistics course at the Federal University of Juiz de Fora.

I have experience in R and Python, working with RShiny applications, automated data collection and cleaning via Selenium, and various types of data analysis and modeling.

Currently, I work with epidemiological data forecasting, developing univariate and multivariate time series models and neural network autoregressive models.

Additionally, work on the development of data pipelines to automate modeling processes.

Link to the epidemiological analysis platform where I work: http://jfsalvandotodos.ufjf.br/#!/

<u>I also act as a statistical consultant for graduate students.</u>

EXPERIENCE

CNPq

Senior Cientific Fellow • Ago 2023 - Currently

- · Responsible for creating pipelines for the automated collection, modeling, and deployment of epidemiological forecasting models.
- Working on the creation of the Fable Count package for modeling count time series data using the Fable framework in R.

UFJF - Jf Salvando Todos

Cientific Fellow • Jun 2021 - Ago 2023

- Development of automated reports for epidemiological data analysis
- Development team for the database currently used on the website
- Interactive data visualization

Statistical Consultant for Postgraduate Students

- Experiments Designing for Chemical Students
- Time Series Analysis and Causal Inference for Economics Students
- Also work with Medicine, Nursing and Architecture Students

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

Statistics - Federal University of Juiz de Fora 2020 - 2024